JESULOBA JOHN ABERE

jesulobajohn@gmail.com ♦ +234 703 186 4774 ♦ Github ♦ LinkedIn ♦ Portfolio

SUMMARY

Forward-thinking Software Engineer with a good understanding of techniques geared towards optimum user experience. Skilled in solving problems with Javascript, Typescript, React and Django. Proud team player focused on achieving project objectives with speed and accuracy.

SKILLS

Languages Javascript,

Javascript, Typescript, Python, C++, Java

Technologies React, Next.js, React-Native, Redux, Zustand, Mobx, Graphql, Git, Django, Node.js, Express,

Cypress, Heroku, Solidity, Tailwind, AWS, styled-components, Docker, React-query, Jest

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Sidebrief

Aug 2022 - present

- Collaborated with product managers and designers to create wireframes, mockups, and prototypes for new web applications, resulting in a 40% decrease in development time.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to identify and address key performance bottlenecks, resulting in a 30% improvement in page load times.
- Developed robust, scalable, modular and API-centric infrastructures that resulted in a decrease of customer complaints by 30%.
- Successfully recommended UI technologies and processes to ensure the versatility and quality of our user interfaces.

Front-end Developer

June 2021 - Aug 2022

Maze-softwares

- Analyzed customer behavior to identify areas of improvement in the user experience, proposed solutions that increased customer satisfaction by 15%.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to streamline process and improve communication, resulting in a 10% increase in efficiency.
- Implemented responsive design principles into all web applications, optimizing mobile user experiences and increasing mobile traffic by 50%.
- Collaborated with UX designers and product managers to ensure creative proposals aligned with design best practices and stakeholder expectations.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science, Federal University of Technology Akure

2017 - 2023

PROJECTS

Audiophile Ecommerce Built an Ecommerce website that aims to cater to all audio needs in one place using ReactJS, Django, Next.js, Graphql and Next-auth for secure Oauth authentication. With a user-friendly interface and seamless checkout process, users can browse and purchase high-quality audio devices with ease. (live url) (code)

Designo Agency Built a website for an imaginary design agency to showcase their work, the website spans 8 pages and is built using Typescript, React, styled-components and email.js for sending emails. it is a visually stunning and user-friendly website that effectively showcases Designo's design services. (live url) (code)